<description>
Thanks to the cooperation of esteemed professional physicians, the San Martino Clinic is able to offer patients a personalized and detailed medical care.
Doctors are working with the most innovative technologies, which provide the necessary support that allows to increase the opportunities of prevention, monitoring and therapy.
The clinic offers many different services in several medical fields , all of them assure maximum respect of everyone’s privacy.
</description>

<ca>
Cardiology is a medical specialty that deals with heart related disorders.
Thanks to his high professional  team the San Martino Clinic is able to offer, to all patients, more and more efficient and updated cures of cardiovascular diseases both congenital and acquired.
The cardiovascular diseases are still today the primary cause of death in the word. Among the most common cardiac diseases there are stable and instable angina and myocardial infarction. The San Martino Clinics boasts the cutting-edge diagnostic equipment.
The high quality of generated images and the subsequent precision of the gathered information, allows the cardiologist to achieve an high diagnostic level.
Echocardiography instead is a  cardiology diagnostic test  that register heartbeat and examines the direction of blood flow. It allows also to verify size and shape of the hearth and to inspection the cardiac valves in order to verify how efficient the heart contraction is.
The ultrasound inspection gives the cardiologist a complete picture when the heart is at rest while the cardiac stress test (ECG or EKG) can measure the capacity of the hearth to respond to a physical stress in checked clinical setting.
The mission of our medical staff is helping the patients in maintaining a healthy heart and prevent future major medical emergencies.  Our commitment is also guides the patients towards a correct life style,  the first step for the prevention of cardiovascular troubles and diseases.
</ca>

<de>Dermatology is the medical branch in charge of studying all skin’s diseases.
Since in certain cases the symptoms are not strictly related to epidermis, but to other different problems, every dermatologic case must be carefully studied. So the dermatologist is the specialist dedicated to prevention, diagnosis and cure of this kind of troubles.
In the dermatologic practice of San Martino Clinic works the best dermatology specialists that, using the most advanced technics of diagnosis and surgery, they do their work in clinical dermatology (psoriasis, acne), allergology, pediatric dermatology and cutaneous mycosis (urticarial, itching, eczema).</de>

<en>The Endocrinologist is a trained physician specialized in the diagnose of diseases related to the glands.
The endocrine system refers to the collection of glands of an organism that secrete hormones, this substances play an important role in regulating and controlling metabolism, breeding, growth and sexual development.
Thyroid, Parathyroid, Pancreas, Adrenals, Apophasis, Pituitary, Ovary and Testicles are all endocrine glands.
The endocrinology practice at San Martino Clinic treats all diseases and dysfunctions of these glands such as diabetes, menopause, osteoporosis, dyslipidemia, infertility , growing defects, calcium and phosphorus metabolism troubles, eating disorders, increase or reduction of hormones production.
In particularly we are specialized in the treatments of thyroid gland, the most important gland of the human body  whose functioning is pivotal for the whole body wellness.
Hyperthyroidism and  Hypothyroidism affect today thousands of people, mostly women.
The symptoms of thyroid gland diseases are often common with those of other illnesses and therefore sometimes difficult to determine.
In the endocrinology practice of San Martino Clinic works senior medics specialized in detecting, treatment and cure of all diseases above descripted.</en>

<fi>The physical therapy or physiotherapy is the medical branch primarily concerned with impairments and disabilities of muscular skeleton apparatus and the promotion of mobility, function ability, quality of life and movement potential through examination, evaluation, diagnosis and physical intervention. No meter which the cause is, in a therapeutically program are applied basic and specialist techniques in order to strike functional rehabilitation and restore the lost abilities. With physiotherapy is also possible to give special treatments under physician indication and intervene in all situations where movement, respiratory or cardiovascular functions have been compromised by  illnesses, congenital defects, accidents or ageing.
All treatments are, not only therapeutic, but also precautionary. Numerous are the therapeutic solutions, in between we find: physical therapy, manipulation therapy, deep massotherapy, kinesitherapy, postural therapy and occupational therapy.
</fi>

<mi>General medicine  is the medical specialty dealing with the prevention, diagnosis and treatment of adult diseases whom treatment is mostly done through drugs or hygienic/sanitary education.
Internal medicine physicians are specialists who apply scientific knowledge and clinical expertise to the diagnosis, treatment and compassionate care of adults across the spectrum from health to complex illness and, if so, directing them to another doctor specialist with a view to offer the best possible care to every patient.
The physician is able to follow the patient at all stages of life; from adolescence to old age and therefore the general medicine practice of San Martino Clinic constitutes the essential reference point for patients of all ages in need for a skilled counselling and a team of expert to whom they can entrust their health.</mi>

<ms>Every human being spends a third of his life sleeping. Sleep functions are different and not yet totally defined, the most important are learning, memory, neuronal growth, energy preservation, thermoregulation, emotions modulation.
The international classification of sleep disorders identifies right now almost 60 disorders sleep related and is esteemed that 15%-20% of the population is affected with negative repercussions on the regulation of all functions listed above.
The Sleep Medicine started to study physiological sleep and related disorders since the 1960s. Presently sleep medicine is a medical specialty that involves several different medical specialist, such as neurologist, psychiatrist, psychologist, lung specialist, otolaryngologist, maxillofacial surgeons, dentists and pediatrics.
Thanks to the cooperation of his highly experienced team , the San Martino Clinic, is a medical center of excellence for diagnosis and cure of sleep disorders both in adults and child.
Here under a list of major sleep disorders:</ms>

<nu>A nutritionist is a specialist who advises on matters of food and nutrition impacts on health both in case of perfect health condition that in case of pathologies.
During the check-up the specialist creates individualized nutritional plans, also working in very close contact with a physician, and paying very close attention to the health state of the patient.
The individual needs are identified and related to nutrition and diet through a detailed interview and once that the nutritional plan is defined, the nutritionist will verify trends and effects.</nu>

<og>At the San Martino Clinic we do pay special attention to all women needs putting at their disposal a gynecology and obstetrics practice of excellence where our specialists follows the patients not only with diagnosis and treatments of gynecologic diseases, but also helping women in step of their life.
Our gynecologists gives an important support to adolescent women during the important stage of the developing of sexual awareness, the prevention and the firsts gynecologic problems.
During fertile age, women are followed in every step of pregnancy and pregnancy research always protecting their health.
During menopause the women are, not only clinically, but also psychologically supported helping them to find a new awareness to be a woman.</og>

<ol>The otolaryngologist is a physician specialized in medical and surgical treatment of ear, nose, throat and head/neck area.At the San Martino Clinic we do offer otolaryngology  treatments both surgical that outpatient thanks to the groundbreaking machineries  that allows our specialists to make diagnosis and find therapies.The services available at the clinic are: Otolaringology exhamination – Laringofibroscopy – Rhinofibroscopy</ol>

<or>The process for reaching a good state of health is the product of teamwork where the protagonist is the patient. At the San Martino Clinic is available the orthopedic practice whom goal is to improve the patient health.</or>

<os>Osteopathy is a type of complementary medicine based on the central role of musculoskeletal system in illness onset and maintenance of a good health state.
The Osteopaths at San Martino Clinic treats patients with manipulation of bones and muscles, often resolving the problem without medicines.
Osteopathy is a specialty that easily lend itself to cooperate with other practices and wards, specifically at San Martino Clinic our Osteopathy team cooperates with:</os>

<se>Senology is the branch of medicine that deals with breast cancer, one of the most common women’s tumors that could be easily identifiable through a mammography.  A mammography is an x-ray examination that allows a qualified specialist to examine the breast tissue for any suspicious areas.  At the San Martino Clinic we use the next generation machineries that allows an accurate breast examination reducing to aminimum the  dose of ionizing radiations.
The actual incidence of breast cancer in feminine population is 8%-10% which means that 8-10 in 100women will be diagnosed with breast cancer in their lifetime and this is the reason why an early detection is extremely important in order to program surgical and therapeutic therapies. The mammography can be realized also on patients with breast implant and in case of dense breast has to be integrated with an ultrasound. Mammograms can often show a breast lump before it can be felt. They also can show tiny clusters of calcium called microcalcifications that could be the first sign of first stage cancer.</se>

<ua>Urology is the branch of medicine that focuses on the surgical and medical diseases of the male and female urinary tract system, and the male reproductive organs. The organs under the domain of urology include the kidneys, adrenal glands, ureters, urinary bladder, urethra, and the male reproductive organs.</ua>

