<description>
	Maxillofacial surgery is the medical specialty dedicated to diagnosis and treatment of diseases (e.g. traumatism, deformity, neoplasia, infection, degeneration…) and esthetic-functional issues affecting mouth, teeth, jaw, face and neck. Dr. Giorgio Pedretti is the head of maxillo-facila surgery at Clinica San Martino. In twenty years of experience he has treated thousands of patients. 
At San Martino Clinic we offer the choice of the right surgery treatment and a constant and meticulous follow-up.
</description>

<orthognatic_surgery>
<ul>
	<li>Correction of dental skeletal malocclusions (mandible’s extension or shortening and jaw-bones extension)</li>
	<li>Chin plastic surgery and profile-plasty</li>
	<li>Maxilla enlargement surgery</li>
	<li>Surgery for orthodontic treatment easing
	<ul>
		<li> Corticotomies</li>
		<li> Segmental osteotomy</li>
		<li> Disinclusion of unerupted teeth</li>
		<li> Mucogingival surgery</li>
	<ul></li>
<ul>
</orthognatic_surgery>
<orthognatic_surgery_title>
Orthognatic Surgery
</orthognatic_surgery_title>

<nose_surgery>
<ul>
	<li>Functional and esthetical Rhynoplasty</li>
	<li>Septoplasty and lower turbinates surgery</li>
	<li>Nasal valve repair</li>
</ul>
</nose_surgery>
<nose_surgery_title>
	Nose Surgery
</nose_surgery_title>

<ear_surgery>
	Otoplasty ( correction of protruding hears)
</ear_surgery>
<ear_surgery_title>
	Ear Surgery
</ear_surgery_title>

<facial_traumatology>
<ul>
	<li>Treatment of facial bones breaking and minor deformities</li>
	<li>Correction of soft tissues and skin deformities further to facial traumas</li>
</ul>
</facial_traumatology>
<facial_traumatology_title>
	Facial Traumatology
</facial_traumatology_title>

<salivary_glands_surgery>
	Salivary glands stone removal
</salivary_glands_surgery>
<salivary_glands_surgery_title>
	Salivary Glands Surgery
</salivary_glands_surgery_title>

<day_surgery>
A team of high experienced anesthetists-resuscitation specialists cooperates routinely with Dr. Pedretti allowing minor surgeries under local and locoregional anesthesia in conscious sedation by inhalation or injection.
Also major surgeries are usually performed with injection anesthesia, the general anesthesia is used only for few selected cases that requires a total control of breathing airways.
In any case all surgery, both in conscious that in total sedation are performed in Day Surgery or One Day Surgery.
Dr. Pedretti’s team boast a large number of clinical cases treated with these procedures, many of which subject of scientific publications and presentations at Italian and European symposium.
</day_surgery>
<day_surgery_title>
	Day Surgery
</day_surgery_title>

<site_ad>
Visit <a href="http://www.gpedretti.pro"> Dr. Pedretti’s official website</a>
</site_ad>