<description>
	More than 30 years of hands on experience. We are so sure of the quality of our service that we offer <a href="http://clinicasmartino.it/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Garanzia-prodotti-amt-ing.pdf">life-long warranty</a>.
</description>
<long_description>
	Dental implantology is a combination of different surgical techniques for the restoration of dental apparatus fully or partially damaged. Dental implants are surgically secured in the maxilla or jawbone and are not visible once placed. They are used to secure fixed or movable prosthesis, in order to provide patients with complete chewing functions. They are made by different materials: titanium with acrylic material, titanium with composite resin  or metal free ceramics. Dental implantology can be employed when there are one or more missing teeth. Specially in partial edentulous cases, the advantage of implantology is that, in contrast to bridges, it is not necessary to file down the adjacent teeth, techniques that have proved to be not endurable because the lifetime of filed teeth is reduced compared with those of uncut teeth. For total edentulous cases the implantology allows to avoid the use of old prosthesis.  The number of implant may vary from a minimum of four on the lower dental arch to a maximum of six on the upper dental arch. Moreover in cases of serious maxilla bones atrophy , the bones reconstructions with additional intervention of bone collection and graft can be avoided applying the zygomatic implants.  Dr Pedretti has been a pioneer in proposing in Italy the method of zygomatic implant anchorage. This technique, without the bones reconstruction of the alveolar ridges, allows the patient to obtain a complete and permanent new set of teeth in a few days. Implantology can be applied to all patients with the exclusion of selected cases with serious health problems.It Generally does not present particular side effects and it is suitable for women of age 16 or older, and men 18 years or older.  The surgery happens in local anesthesia. Vitals, respiratory and cardiac parameters of the patients are constantly supervised by an anesthetist.  The chewing function is completely restored in a short time – maximum 10 days – and teeth look as good as natural. The professionalism and expertise of Dr. Pedretti and his team, altogether with the employment of the groundbreaking machineries and technologies, allows the “San Martino Clinic” to offer the highest quality services at low prices. Thanks to a wide range of clinical solutions we have the possibility to offer high performances and specific techniques to all our patients:  rigorous clinical evaluations guarantees therefore the best results both in medics and esthetics terms. Continuous research and technical improvement, in terms of materials, methodology and technology  has contributed to implantology with meaningful clinical-scientific results. Scientific tests have allowed implant technology to make great breakthroughs. Thanks to an operation room equipped with cutting-edge machineries, the dental team is able to respond to every request, from the easiest to the complex ones. Doctor Giorgio Pedretti started his activity of oral implantology with osseointegration technic in 1986 and ever since he has treated thousands patients  devoting himself to more and more complex cases.
</long_description>
