<description>The odontology department of San Martino Clinic offers the possibility to all patients to enjoy highly professional services.</description>
<more_info>
The Odontology ward is located in the underground floor of San Martino Clinic where we can find an ample waiting room with a special room for children, and the reception/administration room from which it departs two corridors where are located different operating rooms, laboratories and sterilization rooms.
<br>
Every operation room is equipped with x-ray machineries specifically conceived to be easily sterilized in order to guarantee a better security to patients, dentists and their cooperators.
<br>
The working areas are protected by special barriers and decontaminated using special sanitizers after the treatment of each patient.
<br>
The sterilization is made following the most restrictive standards and using autoclaves of class B so that we can guarantee a great protection against every kind of contamination.
<br>
The constant upgrade of the medical team altogether with  the employment of the last generation and technologically advanced equipment, allows the San Martino Clinic to offer the highest quality services at affordable prices.
<br>
The odontology services are besides integrated by the close cooperation with surgical and maxillofacial departments.
<br>
Among the various services offered by the odontology department  of Sna Martino Clinic can be found:
<br>
CONSERVATIVE DENTISTRY whose goal is to maintain the integrity of the tooth in the mouth while successfully treating the problem and preventing a recurrence thanks also to the appliance of the modern esthetic techniques such as
<br>
Filling with material of the same tooth color
Ceramic Inlays or dental veneers
ENDODONTIC THERAPY is a sequence of treatment for the infected pulp of tooth which results in the prevention or elimination of infection on nerve tissues and blood vessels. Endodontic therapy involves the removal of necrotic tissues and the subsequent shaping, cleaning and filling of decontaminated canals.
<br>
PERIODONTAL THERAPY for treatment and care of periodontal tissues  that is the support for the tooth (gingiva, periodontal ligament, cementum and alveolar bone)
<br>
SMALL SURGERIES
<br>
FIX OR REMOUVABLE DENTAL PROSTHESIS necessaries to restore missing or damaged  teeth both for esthetic and functional needs. At the San Martino Clinic we can realize every kind of prosthesis using traditional or modern technics depending on the circumstances.
<br>
ORTHODONTIC whose goal is the correction of muscular, skeleton and dental anomalies in order to  help a correct growth of facial bones for young patients not yet fully developed, and a correct teeth occlusion for adult patients in order to prevent periodontal traumas and temporomandibular joint diseases.
<br>
GNATOLOGYfor the treatment of  temporomandibular joint dysfunctions and problem with mandible’s position. In cooperation with the orthodontist and using particular instruments as bite and plates, the gnatology specialist’s goal is resolve or alleviate several problems as headache, neck pain, muscular pain or tension, muscle fatigue.
<br>
DENTAL CARE, PREVENTIVE DENTISTRY AND BEAUTY TREATMENTS
<br>
DIAGNOSTIC AND RADIOLOGY using high resolutions machineries with minimal X-ray exposure  for diagnostic purposes
<br><br>
<a href="http://clinicasmartino.it/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/ODONTOIATRIA-ING.pdf" class="link">Download the brochure</a></more_info>